Giovani Ocan

giovaniocan@gmail.com | +55 44 998-428-989

GitHub Portfolio Linkedin

I'm a junior developer with a passion for technology with 4+ years of programming experience. I believe that programming has the power to transform people's lives and solve real problems. I seek constant learning and am excited to contribute to challenging projects, improving my skills and driving the team's progress.

Education

Paraná Federal Institute – Campus Goioerê jan 2019 - dez 2022

Computer Technician

• Courses: Compilers, Algorithms, Operating Systems, Data Structures, Programming Logic, React.

Skills

Advanced Skills: Javascript, Typescript, Html, Css, React.js, React Hooks, Git, ContextAPI.

Intermediary Skills: Java, MySQL, Node.js, Next.js. Redux, Zustand, Jest.

Soft Skills: Personal communication, teamwork, problem solving, entrepreneurial and proactive.

Professional Experience and Important Projects

Luna-Bus Paraná, Brazil

Co-Founder and Web-developer - Nov 2022 - Current

- Developing React.js and Next.js tools for municipal public transports
- Built backend applications to integrate and consume on the frontend.

Freelancer Brazil

Desenvolvedor Freelancer - Mar 2023 - Current

- Built on demand software for local businesses.
- Built a landing page for a cheese-bread company, resulting in a 15% increase in sales. The new page allowed for a clear and easy showcasing of their products.
- Responsive Design Implementation and Performance Optimization using SEO techniques
- Collaboration & Feedback: Worked closely with the team and with the customers

Ignite Timer Paraná, Brazil

An appointment scheduling project from a calendar with integration with Google Calendar Apr 2023 – Jun 2023

- Built a fullStack project using React, Node and Prima (mysql).
- The whole project has authentication integration with google
- Utilized Next and Next-Seo generating Search Engine Optimization
- Front-end interfaces designed and implemented to streamline user-driven processes, improving UI/UX through design systems.